NEELKAMAL SAMANTARAY

Address: Unit – III, QR No. S/53, Kharvel Nagar Bhubaneswar 751001, Mob- 7978113936 email id - neelkamal.samantaray@gmail.com

Profile

12 + years of experience in Banking Sales, Operation & Administration.

The detail profile is as follows:

Banking Profile

Dealt high transacting customers.

- Identify depleting customers and control them
- Reduce or improve on band 1 and band 2 customers
- Reduce band 1 and band 2 transactions

Handled cash receipts and payments and ensured transactions are carried out within the prescribed TAT with errors. Cash balancing and cash bundling.

Processing of retail FX postings / gold sales/prepaid cards. Issuance of DD/MC(within prescribed TAT).

Executed funds transfer/FD closure/Account closure etc.

Processed salary uploads, custodian of teller box ,cheque drop boxes, ATM. Ensured error free transactions of receipts and payments, vault custodian. Ensured highest level customer service and outward clearing process.

Capable of using quicken and other forms of banking software like CRM etc.

Sales Profile

Experienced in planning marketing campaigns, getting collateral developed & promoting the product & services.

Maintained good relationship with HNI clients and also worked as financial advisor.

Conducted risk profiling of all mapped clients for better advisory on investment needs and achieved target by managing portfolio clients

Generate leads for different product selling, also generate leads for third party products to the customers.

Operations & Administration Profile

Monitored large amount of movements and identified customers and diverted them to direct banking channels.

Maintained local stationary as per order levels / indent security stationary, process and follow up of admin related bills and payments.

Periodically check vault register, periodic exchange of keys lodged with other branch.

Managed collection, clearing / FCY cheques. Monitoring cash transactions. Report suspicious transactions, suspense accounts, deferred accounts, receivables, reconciling and maintaining of suspense accounts register.

Maintained records of all transactions, stock, voucher etc. Managed the house keeping, Security and customer service staffs.

Collect feedback from customers, record and resolve complaints .

Key Skills

Banking product knowledge Planning and Organizing
Team Management Sales and influencing skills
Communication Awareness of Banking regulations

Professional Experience

Royal Engineer & Construction Role: Area Sales Manager Duration: Aug 2017 till date Roles and Responsibilities:

- I look into the business development.
- Focus on Purchase supplies of equipment for properties.
- Plan and direct the purchase, sale, and development of real estate building.
- Supervise the sales staff and take daily reports on sale.

Achievements: In Royal Engineering & Construction, I got my confirmation of service after six months of my joining. Further I have also got incentive month on month.

INDUSIND BANK LTD. (Key Deputy Manager)

Role: Key Account Manager Duration: Jan 2017 till July 2017

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Managing the portfolio of 3 Crores.
- Monitor and address HNI Clients Banking & Investment requirement.
- Conduct risk profiling of all mapped clients for better advisory on investment needs and achieve target by managing portfolio clients.
- Regular contact with all mapped clients through weekly / monthly calls and resolution of queries of all mapped clients within TAT specified.

Kotak Securities LTD (Acquisition)

Role: Assistant Manager

Duration: Nov 2013 to Dec 2016

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Managing the team & handle the HNI Client.
- Reaching out to all clients on a periodic basis and motivating them to invest through cross selling as many products as possible.
- Processing of Demat account of higher income group persons and guiding in investment.
- Creating new clients for generating investment in shares.

Achievements : In Kotak Securities I got my confirmation of service after six months of my joining. Further I have also got incentives month on month for better work and also got salary hike in a year.

HDFC Bank (Teller and Welcome Desk)

Role: Deputy Manager

Duration: March 2011 to September 2013

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Handling the Teller and welcome desk.
- Looking after the day to day operation of the branch and the audit
- Monthly reporting of day to day functioning of the branch .Finding out ways and means to generate funds for the branch.
- Focus on business development across liabilities, assets & revenues & improved client stickiness.
- Disbursement of the gold loan..

Achievements : In HDFC I got my confirmation of service after six months of my joining. Further I have also got bonus for better work and also got salary hike in a year.

HUTCHISON ESSAR PVT. CO. LT

Role: CORPORATE SALES REPRESENTATIVE at Pune

Duration :Oct , 2006 to Feb, 2011

Roles & RESPONSIBILITIES:

- handled post-paid connection in Corporate Sector of Hutch,
- Discussed the requirements from the company and offered them the best plan as per their requirements,
- Develop & generate new data from existing clients,
- Fulfilling monthly business targets by closing the prospective leads,
- Servicing to the customers to satisfy them through phone calls & visiting to them.

Education

MBA in Marketing : ICFAI University 2006. B.com : Utkal University 2004.

+2 com : CHSE 2001.

Personal Details

DOB: 10th July 1984 **Nationality:** Indian

Marital Status: Married

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the above-furnished information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date: / / Place:Bhubaneswar